KRISHNA VERMA

A2-501,Saarrthi Souvenir,Baner,Pune,Maharashtra - 411045 +91-7349782793 krisv.nit16@gmail.com

Software Engineer-2

S	u	m	m	าล	ry
$\mathbf{\circ}$	u	***		Lu	- y

Software developer with experience in developing back-end, front-end infrastructure and database designs for web applications. Achievement-driven, problem-solving professional with positive attitude targeting assignments in software development with organization. Works well under pressure and consistently meets deadlines and targets while delivering high quality work

Technical Summary

Tech Stack

- Backend Technologies Java 8, C, Node JS
- **Frameworks:** Spring, Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Spring Data JPA, Struts 2.x, Servlet, Hibernate
- WebServices: REST APIs , SOAP WebServices
- Unit Testing JUnit, Spock (Groovy) Framework
- Front End Technolgies HTML,CSS, JavaScript, JSPs
- Libraries and Frameworks React Js, Angular JS, GraphQL, Redux
- RDBMS MySQL, Oracle 12g
- **NoSQL** Amazon DynamoDB, MongoDB
- Build Tools Maven, Gradle, Ant
- AWS Services S3, SQS, Dynamo
- Indexing Solr
- Caching Redis
- Version Control Systems Git, BitBucket/GitHub, SVN
- Operating Systems Linux, Ubuntu, Windows 10
- Container and Orchestrator Docker, Kubernetes
- Deployment Automation Ansible

Core Competencies

- Problem Solving
- Data Structures and Algorithms

Education

2012 - 2016

Bachelor of Technology, Electronics and Communications Engg.

Motilal Nehru National Institute of Technology CGPA- 8.32/10

Work experience

2018 - Present

Software Engineer-2

Talentica Software-Pune, Maharashtra

Responsibilities:

- Developed the complete backend monitor microservices infrastructure for Document fetching from FTP server and integrating it by filtering into Alpha-sense, Al based financial search Engine.
- Developed the complete backend module for Feed Integration of new SEC and Moodys documents provided by APIs in the Alpha-sense for different organisations
- Developed full stack feature of single sign-on from scratch for existing recruitment product TalentPool using Java, SpringBoot, Struts2.x, SAML 2.0 and AngularJS and integrated it with various federation softwares for Identity providers such as Microsoft ADFS, Ping Federate, Okta, OAuth and SSOCircle.
- Worked on different backend modules in multiple projects along with TalentPool simultaneously to develop and improve the existing features using Spring Boot and Java

Accomplishments:

- Developed the complete microservice based backend infrastructure to incorporate the new Feeds, Documents and Content Providers in Alpha-sense entity page.
- Improved the logging feature into multiple application by implementing single sign-on to avoid multiple credentials and improved ease of use.

2016 - 2018 Software Engineer

Mahindra Comviva Technologies

Responsibilities:

- Mapping telecom clients, requirements and providing them best solutions involving evaluation and definition of scope of project and finalization of project requirements.
- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular telecom software products.
- Served as point-of-contact for LMS (Loyalty Management Solution of Mobilytix Suite) for telecom operator client HCPT-Indonesia, IRIS for Banglalink-Bangladesh and LMS for Viettel Vietnam.

Accomplishments:

- Worked on back-end code to optimize the performance by implementing plugin model and upgraded the product with separate processes and improved the TPS by 60%.
- Deployed the product to replace the 8 years long product to improve the performance at the client site in Jakarta, Indonesia.
- Deployed the IRIS solution on production environment in Bangladesh and Vietnam and made it successfully live on client site in strict timelines resolving issues on the go.
- Developed customer care GUI, different kind of reports and different interface types on the go to support the customer requirements along with the widget changes.

Personal Details

- GitHub https://github.com/krisrajaryan27/
- LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/krishna-verma/
- StackOverFlow https://stackoverflow.com/users/6619434/krishna-verma/
- Blog https://learningnirvana.home.blog/
- **Website** https://krisrajaryan27.github.io/Krishna/